Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have nor the gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers,
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation, of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as
maid's servant, nor as ox, nor as nor
anything that is thy neighbors. I read
Exodus 20:es 1-1 17. May the Lord add a
blessing to the reading of this word. In
Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or book will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Jerome.
>> Race and peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother James.
>> Good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Sean.
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question?
>> Uh, yes. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Um,
Tanya Liggins asks, "Will the righteous
be healed in the wilderness that we flee
to or during the gathering to the
wilderness?"
>> All right. So, two different times here,
but brother Jerome, what you got?
Well,
we at the Israel of God, we like to say
if you want to know what the Lord going
to do tomorrow,
see what he did yesterday.
And what I mean by that is, let's take a
look at what he did with Israel when
they were in the wilderness in the past
when they came out of Egypt. So, let's
go to uh Psalms 107.
Psalms 107.
And we going to do some skipping.
Brother James, read verse four and five
and then we gonna skip.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> Psalm 107 verse4 and 5 says, "They
wandered in the wilderness in the
solitary way. They found no city to
dwell in. Hungry and thirsty, their soul
fainted in them."
>> Skip to verse 9.
For he satisfied the longing soul and
fillth the hungry soul with goodness.
>> And skip down to verse 20.
>> He sent his word and healed them and
delivered them from their destructions.
>> Yeah. And so, yeah, he he'saling
in that wilderness. Now, will you say he
healing the righteous and the
unrighteous?
Well, when they free of the uh
wilderness, more than likely ain't
nobody getting in there unless they uh
worthy to get in there. That's the
fleeing. So now um let's let's look at
another example. Let's go to Psalm uh
Isaiah. Let's go to Isaiah 35
and read verse 1-6 and read it as
quickly as you can. Okay. Isaiah 35:1-6
says, "The wilderness and the solitary
place shall be glad for them, and the
desert shall rejoice and blossom as the
rose. It shall blossom abundantly, and
rejoice even with joy and singing. The
glory of Lebanon shall be given unto it,
the excellency of Carmel and Chiron.
They shall see the glory of the Lord,
and the excellency of our God." Well,
this is future. This is talking about
what's going to take place when we flee
into the uh wilderness in the future. Go
ahead.
>> Strengthen ye the weak hands, and
confirm the feeble knees. Say to them
that are of a fearful heart, be strong,
fear not. Behold, your God will come
with vengeance. Even God with a
recompense, he will come and save you.
Then the eyes of the blind shall be
open, and the ears of the deaf shall be
unstopp. Then shall the lame man leap as
in heart, and the tongue of the dumb
sing. For in the wilderness shall waters
break out, and streams in the desert.
>> Okay, last place. Let's go to Psalms 147
and just read verse 1 through3 and
that'll be it.
Okay. Psalm 147:es
1-3 says, "Praise ye the Lord, for it is
good to sing praises unto our God, for
it is pleasant, and praise is comely.
The Lord doeth build up Jerusalem. He
gatherth together the outcast of Israel.
He healed the broken in heart, and
bindeth up their wounds."
>> Yeah. He bindeth up their wounds. He
going to gather his people. He going to
take care of them. If they need healing,
he going to give he going to give them
healing. That's all I got.
>> All right. So, he going to do a new
thing out there. Thank you for that,
brother. As we continue to move on to
our next question,
>> moving on. Leaping lamb asks, "Why
doesn't I OoG blow the trumpet on the
day of trumpet feast?"
All right, brother Julius. How come
there's no sounding of the trumpets
during the day of trumpet feast? Because
there is no Levitical priesthood
today. Let's go to Leviticus the 11th
chapter uh 23rd chapter.
Let's see if the Lord commanded us to
blow the trumpet on the memorial of
blowing a trumpet.
Brother James, Leviticus 23:1 and2
quickly, and then we'll skip to verse
23.
>> Okay. And the Lord spake unto Moses,
saying, Speak unto the children of
Israel, and say unto them concerning the
feast of the Lord, which he shall
proclaim to be holy convocations, even
these are my feast.
>> Skip down to verse four and read that.
These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocations, which he shall
proclaim in their seasons.
>> Skip down to verse 23.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
>> Uhhuh.
>> speak unto the children of Israel,
saying, In the seventh month, in the
first day of the month, shall ye have a
Sabbath, a memorial blowing of trumpets,
unholy convocation.
>> Go ahead. Ye shall do no survile work
therein, but ye shall offer an offering
made by fire unto the Lord.
>> So now we don't read right here where
you have to blow a trumpet. You have a
holy convocation and then Jesus, you
don't do the sacrificial because Jesus
took care of that by him uh eliminating
the sacrificial animals. Now somebody
try to use this on me. Uh Numbers 29.
Numbers 29. And they try to tell me that
this is why we should blow the trumpet.
Numbers 29 and1. When you get it, go
ahead.
>> And in the seventh month, on the first
day of the month, ye shall have unholy
convocation. Ye shall do no survile
work. It is a day of blowing the
trumpets unto you.
>> Now, they're saying this is why you
should blow the trumpet. No, it is the
day of atonement, the day of uh memorial
of blowing of trumpets. Why? Because it
told you in the seventh month and in the
first day of the month, you have a holy
convocation. You don't blow the trumpet.
It is called the memorial of blowing a
trumpet. Then when you read verse two
all the way out throughout which is
which the whole chapters numbers 28 and
29 deal with all of the feasts of the
Lord and they all deal with animal
sacrifices. We don't do that anymore.
Let me show you who really blow the
trumpets and what the memorial trumpets
is really all about. Let's go to
Revelation chapter 8
because everybody is saying well I
should blow the chauffur or the ram's
horn. We I can't read that
the priest blew the trumpets and that
was to gather Israel together. That was
to uh leave the camp, set up camp or for
war, to announce war.
Revelation uh the 8th chapter
and pick it up at verse uh
verse six.
>> Okay,
>> I'm sorry, verse two. Look what John say
he saw.
>> And I saw the seven angels which stood
before God and to them were given seven
trumpets.
>> How many? How many trumpets?
>> Seven trumpets.
>> But who's doing the blowing? Skip down
to verse six and go ahead.
>> And the seven angels which had the seven
trumpets prepared themselves to sound.
>> So the angels do the blowing of the
trumpets, not us. And there is no
Levitical priesthood today.
That's all I got on that. That's why ALG
don't blow no trumpets.
>> Anybody else?
>> Think you hit the nail on the head,
brother. We're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Moving on. Valencia says, "Can you tell
me who is this speaking of in Titus 1
verse 12?"
All right. In the book of Titus,
we're going to go there. Our brother
Dre, take it from there. The book of
Titus, right after second Timothy, who
is that speaking in that Titus 1 and 12.
>> Let's go read that, brother James. And
uh go ahead when you get it.
Titus 1 and verse 12 says one of
themselves even a prophet of their own
said the creations are always liars even
beasts slow bellies. So it doesn't tell
you who it is that says that in here.
Uh, a lot of people attribute it to uh,
this guy named Epimenities
that supposedly said it, but we can't
read that right here in the scripture.
But what it was, Paul was sending out a
letter to Titus and telling him to, you
know, to get ready and pick people out.
Let's start at verse one and we going to
skip and read four and five. Go ahead.
>> Paul, a servant of God and an apostle of
Jesus Christ according to the faith of
God's elect and the acknowledging of the
truth which is after godliness.
>> Now read four and five.
>> To Titus, my own son after the common
faith, grace, mercy, and peace from God
the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ our
Savior. Uhhuh.
>> For this cause left I thee init that
thou shouldest set in order the things
that are wanting and ordained elders in
every city as I had appointed thee.
>> So Titus was to ordain or elders in
every city. And there was some
pre-qualifications for these elders.
Verse six, go ahead.
If any be blameless, the husband of one
wife, having faithful children, not
accused of riot or unruly.
>> For a bishop must be blameless as a
steward of God, not self-willed, not
soon angry, nor given to whine, nor
striker, nor not given to filthy lucery.
Okay. So, it goes on to tell you all of
these qualifications
and then afterwards he lets you know why
he's saying this. Verse 9, go ahead.
Holding fast the faithful word as he had
been taught that he may be able by sound
doctrine both to exhort and to convince
the gainsers.
>> Go ahead.
For there are many unruly and vain
talkers and deceivers, especially they
of the circumcision,
>> whose mouths must be stopped, who
subvert whole houses, teaching things
which they ought not for filthy lucr.
>> So they were incrementing, they was
teaching all kind of stuff and they did
it for filthy lucr. He said, "There be
many vain talkers and deceivers." And he
said, "Especially they of the
circumcision." And then he talked about
this prophet of their own
who says that they are liars and evil
beast slowbellies, but it does not give
you that person's name. So that's all I
got on that.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
>> As we move on to our next question,
>> next question. Melon Natural Journey
asks, "Are we allowed to have crystals?"
>> All right. So, Brother Dre, are you
allowed to have crystals?
>> Well, you know, you you got a crystal
glass you drink out of. Some people have
crystal chandeliers.
It it actually just depends on what you
using the crystal for. Some people got
crystal balls they use for divination.
When I was a a youngster, they had a
black ball with some words on it and you
ask the question, shake the ball up and
then after you shake the ball, it gives
you an answer.
And so your question is answered
according to that ball.
And if you're not using it for that, I
don't see nothing wrong with a crystal
glass or a crystal chandelier, as long
as you not using it for some form of
deonation or calling on a spirit to to
do something with. That's all I got.
>> All right. Yes, sir. Indeed. And stay
away from them houses that deal with
them crystal balls. Right, brother? Yes,
sir.
>> All right, we go move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Darnell Avery asks, "What
days are we supposed to fast?"
>> When it come to fasting, Brother Julius,
what days?
>> Let's go to You can fast anytime you
want to, but there's one day that the
Lord commands a fast. Leviticus the
23rd, Brother James. Okay.
Leviticus the 23rd chapter and let's do
this again. Uh 1 and two. Will you go
ahead and get it, brother?
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
"Speak unto the children of Israel, and
say unto them concerning the feast of
the Lord, which ye shall proclaim to be
holy convocations, even these are my
feast."
>> Give me verse four again.
These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocations, which ye shall
proclaim in their seasons. Skip down to
verse 27. And this is when the Lord
commands a fast. Go ahead.
>> Also, on the 10th day of the seventh
month, there shall be a day of
atonement. It shall be an holy
convocation unto you, and ye shall
afflict your souls, an offer an offering
made by fire unto the Lord. We don't do
the offering thing cuz that's animal
sacrifice stuff. But what we do, we
afflict our souls by meditating and
prayer, meditation, prayer, and study in
the word of God and doing what the Lord
said and fasting. That means no food, no
drinks, uh uh no personal pleasures,
none of that. Sisters and brothers, give
me verse 28.
And ye shall do no work in that same
day. For it is a day of atonement to
make an atonement for you before the
Lord your God. So because the Lord
suffered for us, we show him that we
appreciate him what he did for for us by
by uh keeping his commandments, his day
of atonement and afflicting ourselves
with fasting, prayer, and meditation in
the word of God. That's all I got. The
day of atonement.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. M Brazius says, "What were the
other ordinances
terminated along with the sacrificial
ones?"
>> All right. So, what were the ordinances
that were terminated along with the
termination of the sacrificial ones?
Guess caller.
>> Yeah. And the only one that was
terminated that uh uh uh was the one
that uh was put out there to stop us
from sinning or remind us not to sin.
And the only one that uh that was is the
uh fringes. Go to numbers the 15th
chapter read 33- 40.
>> Okay. Numbers 15 33-4
says,
"And they that found him gathered
sticks, brought him unto Moses and
Aaron, and unto all the congregation,
and they put him."
>> Now, there was a man out there gathering
sticks on the Sabbath day, okay? And he
wasn't supposed to do that, and they
didn't know what to do with him. So,
what did they do with him? Go ahead. And
they put him inward because it was not
declared what should be done to him
put him put him in ward. In other words,
they locked him up. Go ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, the man
shall be surely put to death. All the
congregation shall stone him with stones
without the camp.
And all the congregation brought him
without the camp and stoned him with
stones, and he died as the Lord
commanded Moses. And the Lord spake unto
Moses, saying, speak unto the children
of Israel, and bid them that they make
them fringes in the borders of their
garments throughout their generations,
and that they put upon the fringe of the
borders a ribbon of blue. and and it
shall be unto you for a fringe that ye
may look upon it and remember all the
commandments of the Lord and do them and
they and that ye seek not after your own
heart and your own eyes after which you
use to go ahoring.
Now that is uh what he said because you
know put the fringes on so you will look
at them and remember. Did you finish
that?
>> Yes.
>> That you look up on the fringes and
remember not to sin against God.
So now God made so so the only reason
for you to wear the fringes was to
remind you to keep God's commandments.
There was no other reason. Okay, now
let's go and see what happened. Let's go
into Jeremiah 31 and we're going to read
from verse 31
to uh um
34.
>> Okay.
>> Jeremiah 31
and ver chapter 31 from 31 to 34. Go
ahead when you get it. It says, "Behold,
the days come, sayeth the Lord, that I
will make a new covenant with the house
of Israel and with the house of Judah,
not according to the covenant that I
made with their fathers, in the day that
I took them by hand, by the hand, to
bring them out of the land of Egypt,
which my covenant they break, although I
wasn't husband unto them, sayaeth the
Lord."
>> Go ahead. But but this shall be the
covenant that I will make with the house
of Israel after those days, sayeth the
Lord. I will put my law in their inward
parts, and write in write it in their
hearts, and will be their God, and they
will be my people. And they shall teach
no more every man his neighbor, and
every man his brother, saying, "Know the
Lord." For they shall all know me, from
the least of them unto the greatest of
them, sayeth the Lord. For I will give
them their iniquity. I will forgive
their iniquity, and I will remember
their sin no more.
Now, this is the new covenant he's going
to make. And when did they make that new
covenant? Let's go into Hebrews the 10th
chapter and and we going to read one and
and then uh uh we're going to skip as we
go along.
Hebrews chapter 10.
>> Okay. Hebrews chapter 10 verse1 says for
the law having a shadow of good things
to come and not the very image of the
things can never with those sacrifices
which they offered year by year
continually make the comers there unto
perfect.
>> Okay, skip down to verse four and to
tell you why.
For it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and of goats should take away
sins.
>> Okay,
>> you read.
>> Wherefore, when he cometh into the
world, he saith, sacrifice an offering
thou wouldest not, but a body has thou
prepared me.
Go ahead. in burnt offerings and
sacrifices for sin. Thou has had no
pleasure.
Then said, uh,
>> now Jesus, you know, the blood of the
bulls and goats couldn't remove sin.
>> So prepared a body for Jesus cuz that
body needed to be sacrifice. What verse
what what verse are you at now?
>> That was verse six. We're at verse
seven.
>> Skip down to verse 10. Verse 10 says,
"By the which will we are sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for all." So Jesus
needed a body that could be sacrificed
for the sins of the people. Now skip
down to verse 14. Let's see what
happened after it was sacrificed. 14 and
through 16.
>> Okay,
>> go ahead. For by one offering he hath
perfected forever them that are
sanctified.
Whereof the Holy Ghost also is a witness
to us. For after that he had said
before, this is the covenant that I will
make with them after those days, sayeth
the Lord, I will put my laws into their
hearts, and in their mind will I write
them.
So now he's letting you know that look
them same uh laws that the fringes were
supposed to uh uh uh uh keep me from
breaking
didn't work. And the animals that was
killed for sin didn't work. So he said
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
replace the animals with my body
and uh uh uh as far as the laws are
concerned instead of you putting on
fringes to remind you which didn't work.
I'm going to put the fringes in your
mind.
Now once Jesus died
fringes was terminated.
And I give you a good example.
Let's go into Acts the 21st chapter.
And this is when Paul when when the
people of the Jews was trying to kill
Paul and the Greeks came and took them
out of Israel's hand, the Jews hand by
force cuz they was going to kill him cuz
they thought he had took some had taken
some Gentiles into the temple. And let's
show you what happened. Acts 21 and
we're going to start reading at verse
37.
21 and 37.
Read it when you get there. Acts 21-37
says, "And as Paul was to be led into
the castle, he said unto the chief
captain, may I speak unto thee? Who
said, can thou speak Greek?" Now,
>> he wanted to know, "May I speak unto
you?" He said, "Can you speak Greek?"
Now read verse 38 and 39. Go ahead.
>> Art not thou that Egyptian which before
these days made us an uproar and led us
out into the wilderness 4,000 men that
were murderers. But Paul said
>> if fr was our culture like some of the
brothers are saying then Paul would had
them fringes on. You know that
>> right? Mhm.
>> of before Paul uh uh was was uh cut out
to be the uh uh uh apostle to the
Gentiles, he was a Pharisee and he said
he was a strict of the Pharisee. As far
as the law concerned, he was perfect. So
he would have had on every friend that
you supposed to have. But why didn't he
have that is because you are under the
new covenant now. And Paul told you,
read verse verse 39.
>> But Paul said, I am a man which am a Jew
of Tarsus, a city in Silosa, a citizen
of no mean city, and I beseech thee,
suffer me to speak unto the people.
Okay. So now I let you know Paul a
devout Israelite
could have had on fringes
under if we and he would have had if he
was under the old covenant but under the
new covenant after Jesus and died for
the sins of the people the fringes was
terminated with animal sacrifice. That's
all I have to say.
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question. as we continue to move right
on along.
>> Yes. Moving on. Uh Solomon TV says, "I
was addressed about slavery in the
Bible. Shadow enslavement being promoted
in Leviticus 25 41-43.
uh the second class rating and
degragation
of women in Exodus 21 and sexual assets
to virgins in Deuteronomy 22 or a nearby
chapter.
His question is, "Can you please clarify
if child slavery and raping is
acceptable in the Bible?
Well, first of all, you added one too
many scriptures. We ask you to keep it
to a two scripture maximum, but the
guest caller will take it from there.
Okay, the answer to that is no and no.
Let's look at the slavery part. Let's
look at what it's really talking about.
Leviticus 25 and we going to read verse
39 and 40.
>> Okay. Leviticus 25 verse uh 39 and 40
says, "And if thy brother that dwelleth
by thee be wax and poor and be sold unto
thee, thou shalt not compel him to serve
as a bond servant.
But as an hired servant, and as a
sjourer, he shall be with thee, and
shall serve thee unto the year of
Jubilee."
See now that's a his brothers them
polish. So actually they was doing him a
favor.
So he wasn't no like a channel of
slavery even they called that. He said
the Lord said no you do to them just
like a servant. And what they had
indented service.
So hey he couldn't feed himself couldn't
feed his family. So his neighbor said
you come over here and work. I'll feed
you and your family
>> until uh uh until times get better and
then you let them go on on the on the
yield jubilee.
So no, slavery is not condoned. Never
will. But indigenous servants could when
a man or woman couldn't feed themselves
then they could be as indigenous
servants.
So the Bible don't condone slavery. Now
as far as uh uh raping women is
concerned, go to Deuteronomy the 22nd
chapter and read verse 25.
Deuteronomy 22 and verse 25 says, "But
if a man find a betrod damsel in the
field, and the man force her and lie
with her, then the man only that lay
with her shall die."
So now in other words, he going to get
killed for doing that, stoned to death
or whichever way, but either way it go,
he's going to die if he going to force
this woman.
>> So that sound like rape is condoned in
there.
>> No,
>> I think it was question that uh uh
would been much better if had a little
more thought about it. And if you really
thought about it and you looked at the
word of God, you wouldn't have answered
it. Ask it. That's all I have to say.
All right, we're going to leave it right
there as we move move on to our next
question with a time check.
>> Yes, next question. The time is 806.
He also asks, "What about the NRSV
Bible?" Saying it was suggested to me
over the KJV Bible. Is it better? And
why do we read the KJV?
>> All right. First of all, the NRSV. No,
it is not better. It's the King James
Bible where they went in with the NRSV
and pulled out and added in how they saw
fit on some of the issues. Now, the NRSV
is a new revised standard version.
And so when you look at the word revise,
it means to alter or to improve or to
correct, to update, to make a new
version of. Now, if you had the King
James Bible, why would you have to go in
and make a NRSV, an updated version?
Because the NRSV
also, it was published in 1989.
The King James Bible had been around way
back 1600s, right, Julius?
>> Yes, sir.
>> And so it says that the the NRSV that
you asked about was published in 1989 by
the National Council
of Churches and was updated by 30
scholars where their opinions were
included and it was approved by the
Catholic Church and other denominations.
Now the big difference between the King
James version and the NRSV was the King
James was written on a basis of wordto-
word transfer. The NRSV was included 30
scholars who went in with their opinions
and put in what they wanted to put in
and etc. But let's see the King James
version. Let's go to second Peter 1,
brother James. Second Peter 1.
And while we're turning there, brother
Cornell, there are 30,000 changes uh uh
in words in the new uh standard revised
version which was lately updated in
2021.
>> I got some more information on that
also, brother.
>> Yeah. So, that right there tell us that
uh well, let's see if this book even if
the King James Bible even needed any
changes. Second Peter 1 and pick it up,
brother. Read that. 20 and 21. Go ahead.
>> Knowing this first, that no prophecy of
the scripture is of any private
interpretation.
>> You see, they had 30 scholars and other
people that came in with their own
private interpretation, adding in and
making changes like brother Julius said.
Go ahead. For the prophecy came not in
old time by the will of man, but holy
men of God spake as they were moved by
the Holy Ghost.
>> So if the prophecy came in the old time
by the will of man, but holy men of God
spake as they were moved by the Holy
Ghost, then that means that this book
didn't need no help at all. And let's
further prove that, brother. Let's go
into Deuteronomy 4. Deuteronomy the 4th
chapter.
Deuteronomy 4 and read that verse two.
And then we got one more we're going to
go to. Deuteronomy 4 and two. Go ahead.
>> Deuteronomy 4 and verse two says, "Ye
shall not add unto the word which I
command you, neither shall ye diminish
ought from it, that ye may keep the
commandments of the Lord your God, which
I command you."
So here it is for the Old Testament
Christians that this book didn't need
anybody to come in and add to or take
away from the word because it was
written by holy men as they were
inspired by the Holy Ghost. Now go into
Revelation 22.
>> Revelation 22. And we're going to read
two verses out of there also
because this book we are reading out of
right now is the only one you need to
get salvation and eternal life.
>> That's right.
>> Revelation 22. Read 18 and 19. Brother,
let's back up the Old Testament so that
the New Testament Christians can see
this also. Go ahead.
For I testify unto every man that
heareth the words of the prophecy of
this book. If any man shall add unto
these things, God shall add unto him the
plagues that are written in this book.
>> You don't want no plagues. Read the next
verse. And if any man shall take away
from the words of this book of the pro
of this prophecy, God shall take away
his part out of the book of life and out
of the holy city and from the things
which are written in this book. So
nobody is even take away because if
you're going to take away from the
original form of the book and then start
placing your own stuff in that means you
are taking away and adding in and you
don't want to bring this problem upon
yourself. Also the King James Bible is
the Bible that matches up the greatest
with world history.
So those two go hand in hand to give
man, every man, woman, and child
salvation that is written in the pages
of the book. So no, the N RSV
is not the book that you need to be
reading out of. Just read out of the
King James Bible and save your soul from
this unto generation. Brother Julius,
you have something else you want to add?
>> Yes, real quick. Real quick. Uh James,
could you read Mark 11 and verse 26?
>> Sure. Mark 11 and verse 26
>> says, "But if ye do not forgive, neither
will your father which is in heaven
forgive your trespasses."
>> Now that's Mark 11:26 in the NRSVE,
which is the latest name of it, Cornell,
which means updated uh edition. Okay,
brother Dre,
>> do you have the NRSV Mark 11?
Could you read verse 27?
>> Is nothing there?
>> Huh?
>> Nothing is there. It's just 26 and
nothing is there.
>> So it jump from 20 what? 26 to what?
>> It jumps from 25 to 27.
>> So Mark 11:26 is omitted. John 5:4
omitted. Luke 17:36 omitted. Romans
16:24 missing omitted and somebody is
telling you to upgrade to the NISB from
the KJB surely they are trying to take
your salvation from you that's all I got
>> that's right so hey very popular
question and please take heed to what
you just heard and we hope that that
answered your question there as we move
on to our next
>> the next one
next question Sanders Herring asks asked
when is a woman your wife? uh scriptures
given which are too many are Genesis 2
verses 18 22 24 and 25 Genesis 4 1
Exodus 22 16 and Deuteronomy 22 28 and
when is a woman your wife
>> all right send hearing. You have went
over our limit too. We ask you to keep
it to a two scripture maximum. You have
went to four. But let's see how the
guest caller would like to shed some
light on that question.
It depends on the custom of the nation
of the people that you are among.
>> Now in Genesis, he named one when when
Adam and Eve uh uh was called husband
and wife.
They hadn't touched one another.
Then uh uh Joseph
and Mary because husband and wife
and uh Joseph hadn't touched her because
she had not uh uh uh you know because
because and he was going to put her away
when she come up pregnant with Jesus.
But the angel tried to tell had to tell
him. But again too when uh uh uh uh he
said if a man I'm not I'm just quoting
since he decided to quote a lot of stuff
is that if a man should entice a a a
maiden that's not uh uh uh uh connected
with nobody then he shall uh uh endow
her to marry him
>> and then in the days of Jesus I'm read
one pl I'm read one place there and
after that then uh you
Take it where you want it. Let's go into
St. John the 2 chapter. We going to read
1 and two.
Okay. John the 2 chapter 1 and two says,
"And the third day there was a marriage
in Canaa of Galilee, and the mother of
Jesus was there, and both Jesus was
called and his disciples to the
marriage.
So now they had a wed that's a formal
thing. So that means there some vows
going to be swapped. Okay. And we going
to read uh and and we'll read one other
pl uh two other places. Go to 1
Corinthians 7 and read verse one and
two.
1 Corinthians 7:es
1 and 2 says,
"Now concerning the things whereof ye
wrote unto me, it is good for a man not
to touch a woman. Nevertheless, to avoid
fornication, let every man have his own
wife and let every woman have her own
husband."
>> Yes, sir. that. So that mean that
somebody has got to go through some kind
of verbal or written contract
>> just like it is in America. And it was
just like that in Israel. Let me show
you why. This is last place. Go to
Deuteronomy the 24th chapter
and we're going to read vers uh uh uh
verse one.
>> Okay. Deuteronomy 24 and verse 1 says,
"When a man hath taken a wife and
married her, and it come to pass that
she find no favor in his eyes, because
he hath found some uncleanness in her,
then let him write her a bill of
divorcement and give it in her hand and
send her out of his house."
So now, if you have to give a written
divorce, that mean you had to have
something written to get married.
That is correct.
>> So you married when you So the marriage
come with the vow not the sexual act
with the vow. Sexual act just uh uh uh
uh just consummates it
through this country here that you in.
You have to go down and get you some
marriage license. Then you have to go to
the justice of priest or get you a
preacher somewhere and you vow vows.
It's like I think it was in Malachi
either Micah where the Lord say about
you being treacherous with the wife of
your youth and the wife of your uh uh uh
um was it the wife of your uh uh uh
>> the wife of your your youth
>> and your covenant?
>> Yeah, that's Malachi sir.
>> Uhhuh. That mean that
marriage is when you make a vow. It
happened in Israel in the old happened
in Israel in the new and it happened in
this country and most other countries.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. So hope that
>> listen make a vow with marriage license.
>> Right.
>> Thought I throw that in there.
>> Brother
going to tell her sister, I vow that you
my wife. Uhuh. That don't work. That's
all I have to say.
>> Yep. Better than married than the burn.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question as we continue to move
right on along.
>> Moving along. Sandra Herring also asks,
"Is it possible to make the kingdom of
Jesus and not make the kingdom of God?"
>> All right. So
>> I believe you talking about the kingdom
of Jesus and the father's kingdom. So is
it possible to make the kingdom of Jesus
and not make the father's kingdom? Let's
go in and read and let's see what the
book tells us here. Let's go into Isaiah
65.
Isaiah 65.
>> Because as long as you got flesh and
blood
people, you're still going to have some
people sinning. and sinning will get you
in trouble with God quick, fast, and in
a hurry. Let's go to that Isaiah 65 and
let's pick it up at that verse 18 and
let's see what's said here because this
is in Jesus kingdom here.
Go ahead. Okay. But be glad and rejoice
forever in that which I create. For
behold, I create Jerusalem a rejoicing
and her people a joy.
>> Yes.
>> And I will rejoice in Jerusalem in joy
in my people. And the voice of weeping
shall be no more heard in her, nor the
voice of crying.
>> Now, let's talk about this sinner here.
Go ahead.
There shall be no more than an infant of
days, nor an old man that hath not
filled his days. For the child shall die
a hundred years old. But the sinner
being a 100 years old shall be a cursed.
>> So hey, it's still sin going on and
being a cursed does not look good for
the one that is doing the sinning. Now
turn over also to Ezekiel 20. Let's go
there right quick.
before going into
the land. Also, let's see what it says
in Ezekiel 20 and pick it up, brother,
that verse 35. Ezekiel 20 and35. Go
right ahead.
and I will bring you into the wilderness
of the people, and there will I plead
with you face to face.
>> Like as I
>> go ahead
>> like as I pleaded with your fathers in
the wilderness of the land of Egypt, so
will I plead with you, sayeth the Lord.
>> And we know a lot of our forefathers
didn't get out of that wilderness. What
else he say here? Go ahead. and I will
cause you to pass under the rod. And I
will bring you into the bond of the
covenant,
>> and I will purge out from among you the
rebels, and them that transgress against
me. I will bring them forth out of the
country where they sjorn, and they shall
not enter into the land of Israel, and
ye shall know that I am the Lord. The
Lord is going to be purging out the
rebels. The ones that still want to kick
against him. You going to have a problem
big time. Would anybody else like to
add?
>> Yeah. I like to put a real wrinkle in
it.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You going to make both of them
>> because if you done right, you going to
be God.
If you done wrong, you going to be in
the lake of fire.
>> And it's going to be in both kingdoms.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you for that wrinkle.
Needed to put that in there for sure.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question with a time check.
>> Time check 823.
TX Domino says, "One day with God is
like a thousand years, and God gave us
seven days. But in Genesis when he ends
each day he says the evening and the
morning. How does this compute with a
thousand years being one day or is it
not literally a thousand years?
>> All right, brother Jerome, would you
please help them out?
>> Yes, it's literally um a thousand years,
you know. Uh, but the way the Lord
account
and the way the Lord had man account
is a little different. And I'll show you
what I mean by that when we go to
Genesis. But before we go to Genesis,
go to uh second Peter the 3 chapter and
read verse 8. And then we going to go to
Genesis after that.
>> Okay.
Second, I mean um second Peter 3:8 says,
"But beloved, be not ignorant of this
one thing, that one day is with the Lord
as a thousand years, and a thousand
years as one day."
>> Just keep in mind it said with the Lord,
>> one day is as a thousand years. Okay.
Now, let's go to Genesis.
Your question was really based on
Genesis in these thousand years when he
created
uh the days.
Okay,
go to Genesis. Pick it up at uh verse
one, read it to the two.
>> Okay,
go ahead. In the beginning, God created
the heaven and the earth. And the earth
was without form and void, and darkness
was upon the face of the deep, and the
spirit of God moved upon the face of the
waters.
>> Okay? So, in that verse two, he talked
about it said darkness was upon the face
of the deep. And the reason why I'm
pointing that out because he ain't
create no light yet.
Okay? Read verse 3-5.
And God said, "Let there be light." And
there was light. And God saw the light
that it was good. And God divided the
light from the darkness. And God c
>> That That was verse. Go ahead. Verse
five. Go ahead.
>> And God called the light day, and the
darkness he called night, and the
evening and the morning were the first
day.
>> Nah. He he he created light now. So now
he counting days, right? But you notice
I want to point out something. This
ain't the sun and the moon.
Okay? So when he created that first
light, he said in the evening and the
morning was the first day. All right? So
we talking what God is looking at when
he see night and day. even before a sun
and a moon would even came into
existence. So when you talking about a
thousand years, it's one day and I mean
it's a nighttime and a daytime, right?
Before you even have a sun and a moon,
all right? So that's why it said the
evening and the morning were the first
day. Well, you say, "Well, that's a
thousand years." And yeah, cuz you
talking about the first light that God
created. Ain't got nothing to do with
shining no light on this earth. All
right. So now uh read verse 6 and 7.
>> And God said, "Let there be a firmament
in the midst of the waters, and let it
divide the waters from the waters." And
God made the firmament, and divided the
waters which were under the firmament
from the waters which were above the
firmament. And it was so. Mhm. And so
now
what's
in that water, you know, where they talk
about under the firmament,
you know, and then he had a firmament.
He had something called earth is what
I'm trying to get to. Okay? He created
an earth that was in that body of water
that was under the firmament. And he
caused the dry land to appear and he
called it earth. Right? So, did we read
that verse 6 and 7?
>> Yes.
>> All right. Go ahead and read verse 9 and
10.
>> And God said, "Let the waters under the
heaven be gathered together unto one
place, and let the dry land appear, and
it was so."
>> And God called the dry land earth, and
the gathering together of the waters
called he seas. And God saw that it was
good.
>> All right. And now that first light that
he created, it ain't shining through
that first body of water to the earth.
So the Lord created some more lights to
give life upon the earth. And that's
when you start talking about that
24-hour account
in relationship to the sun and the moon.
That ain't got nothing to do with that
first light.
Okay?
>> All right. So now read verse 14 and 15.
And God said, "Let there be lights in
the firmament of the heaven to divide
the day from the night, and let them be
for signs, and for seasons, and for
days, and years."
>> Mhm.
>> And let them be for lights in the
firmament of the heaven to give light
upon the earth. And it was so.
>> Because if the first light was given
light upon the earth, he would need to
create these two lights. Right? So now
when you talk about that thousand years,
a day to is a thousand years. Remember
he created that first light. And he said
the evening and the morning was the
first day and that day is a thousand
years. But then when he created that sun
and the moon to give light upon the
earth, that's when you start dealing
with that 24 hours. You count it. You
get you you you know uh however many
days, 30 days. Then you got a month.
Then you count 12 months. That's a year.
and you count 12 years,
right?
You know, you just keep down until you
get to a thousand years with them
24-hour days of evening and the morning,
but that ain't talking about that first
light. Okay.
>> All right. So, that's all I got on if
anybody uh First Timothy, it talk about
that. I want to quote that then I'm
going give it to the panel if they want
to add something. Can you add that first
Timothy chapter 6 and read verse 14- 16
>> and talk about that first light that was
created. Ain't no man ever seen this
light.
>> Okay.
>> That's right.
>> First Timothy 6 verse 14 and 16.
>> Okay.
>> 14- 16.
>> Yeah.
that thou keep this commandment without
spot, unrebukeable unto the appearing of
our Lord Jesus Christ, which in his
times he shall show, who is the blessed
and only potentate, the King of Kings
and Lord of Lords, who only hath
immortality, dwelling in the light,
which no man can approach unto, whom no
man has seen, nor can see, to whom be
honor and power everlasting. Amen.
>> Yeah, that's all I got.
[Music]
>> All right.
>> Also, brother Jerome, a day is it starts
with the evening and the morning. It
doesn't start with the morning and the
evening. Am I correct?
>> That's correct.
>> So, a day is the evening and the
morning. That's a day.
>> That's a day.
>> Yeah. Evening to evening completes one
day.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Glad you put that Timothy in
there, brother. Hope that answered that
question. as we move on to our next
>> next one. Uh, call me Karen says,
"Concerning the circumcision because of
Acts 15:es
24- 29.
Does that mean modernday Christians do
not need to be circumcised?
If so, what scriptures show that we
still need to be circumcised?
>> Well, first of all, no, that doesn't
mean that the circumcision is not still
relevant even of this day. But I'd like
to open this up to the panel, but let's
go to that Acts 15 first
and they want to read that 24 through 29
and um listen. All right, guest caller.
Go right ahead.
>> I got this. All right,
>> go read it.
>> Okay. Acts 15 24-29
says, "For as much as we have heard as
I'm sorry, for as much as we have heard
that certain which went out from us have
troubled you with words, subverting your
souls, saying, Ye must be circumcised,
and keep the law, to whom we have gave
no such commandment."
It seemed good unto us, being assembled
with one accord, to send chosen men unto
you, with our beloved Barnabas and Paul,
men that have hazarded their lives for
the name of our Lord Jesus Christ. We
have sent thee before Judas and Silas,
who shall also tell you the same things
by mouth. For it seemed good to the Holy
Ghost and to us to lay upon you no
greater burden than these necessary
things, that ye abstain from meats,
offered to idols, and from blood, and
from things strangled, and from
fornication, from which if ye keep
yourselves, ye shall do well, fair ye
well.
>> Now, the first thing is, you notice
what's was what's absent from all of
that.
Thus said the Lord.
>> There you go.
>> He said it seemed good to us.
It seemed good to the Holy Ghost. But it
says, "Thus said the Lord." And the
first thing is the people that dealing
with this, it was never a question about
Israel being circumcised.
This argument was here was over the
Gentiles.
Now, let me show you what happened to uh
uh uh Timothy who had a Greek father,
but he had a Hebrew mother. Go to Acts
16 and read verse 1-3.
>> Okay. Acts 16 1-3 says, "Then came he to
Derby and Lististra. And behold, a
certain disciple was there named
Timothus, the son of a certain woman,
which was a Jewish, and believed, but
her father, but his father was a Greek,
which was well reported of by the
brethren that were at Lististra and
Iconium. him would Paul have to go forth
with him and took and circumcised him
because of the Jews which were in those
quarters for they knew all that his
father was a Greek.
>> Listen, Paul them the 12 apostles down
and I mean when I say arug them down
to avoid uh uh circumcising the Gentiles
but then he turned around and he
circumcised Timothy. What was the
difference if if the circumcision was
was terminated,
>> right?
>> But he had a a a a Hebrew mother.
So now this whole thing was about the
circumcision of the Gentiles. Had
nothing to do with Israel or anybody
else. Let's go into Acts. But we in
Acts, Acts 21
and read verses 18- 25. So let's see
what took place there. So they start
saying that look Paul is is is among the
Gentiles is saying that the young Jews
don't have to be circumcised. But let's
see what they said. Acts 21 18 to2.
>> It says and the day following Paul went
in with us unto James and all the elders
were present. And when he had saluted
them, he declared particularly what
things God had wrought among the
Gentiles by his ministry.
And when they heard it, they glorified
the Lord and said unto him, "Thou
seeest, brother, how many thousands of
Jews there are which believe, and they
are all zealous of the law, and they are
in and they are informed of thee, that
thou teachest all the Jews, which are
among the Gentiles, to forsake Moses,
saying that they ought not to circumcise
their children, neither to walk after
the customs.
What is it?
>> That's what they was telling Paul. So
now the people saying that you among the
Gentiles, European saying that uh you
don't have to uh uh circumcise the uh
Israelites either. But they going to let
him know, but we know that you ain't
saying that. Keep reading.
>> What is it therefore? The multitude must
needs come together, for they will hear
that thou art come. Do therefore this
that we say to thee, we have four men
which have a vow on them. Take them and
purify thyself with them, and be at
charges with them, that they may shave
their heads, and all may know that those
things whereof they were informed
concerning thee, are nothing, but that
thou thyself also walketh orderly, and
keepest the law, as touching the
>> and and what he saying to you, you go go
in in with these guys, so you can show
them that you are not over there out
there teaching that Israel should not be
circumcised.
>> But concerning the Gentiles, what does
it say? Go ahead.
>> As touching the Gentiles which believe,
we have written and concluded that they
observe no such thing, save only that
they keep themselves from things offered
to idols and from blood and from
strangled and from fornication.
Now that so he said, "Look, uh, uh, we
know that you you keep the law. You
ain't out there teaching that Israel
shouldn't be circumcised, but as far as
the Gentiles is concerned, well, we
well, we wrote a letter saying that they
didn't have to do that."
Now, it was never about Israel. But then
again, too, I'm going to raise the
argument of God concerning the
circumcision. Remember God is the one
and even the prophets like you are moved
early the prophets was spoken they was
moved by the Holy Ghost. Now we're going
to look at the circumcision who
instituted this circumcision. Let's go
into Genesis the 17th chapter.
>> Yes sir.
>> We're going to read verse one and two
and we going and we going to skip down
and 10 to 14.
>> Okay. Genesis 17:es 1 to2 says, "And
when Abram was 90, 90 90 years old and
nine, the Lord appeared to Abram and
said unto him, I am the Almighty God.
Walk before me, and be thou perfect, and
I will make my covenant between me and
thee, and will multiply thee
exceedingly."
Get down.
>> Verse 10 says, "This is my covenant
which ye shall keep between me and you
and thy seed after thee. Every man
child."
>> Wait a minute. Who's talking here?
>> The Lord
>> God.
>> Lord.
>> He's talking to Abraham, ain't he?
>> Yes, sir.
>> He's giving him some unsolicited
information and an unsolicited
commandment.
M
>> now
go ahead
>> back at the top of 10 it says this is my
covenant which ye shall keep between me
and you and the and thy seed after thee.
Every man shall listen that's God's
covenant. Didn't he say this is my
covenant?
>> Yes sir.
>> How do you figure the apostles and Paul
can break God's covenant?
>> Can't do it.
Keep reading.
>> Every manch child among you shall be
circumcised,
>> and ye sh and ye shall circumcise the
flesh of your foreskin, and it shall be
a token of the covenant betw twix me and
you.
And he that is 8 days old shall be
circumcised among you, every manchild in
your generations. He that is born in the
house or bought with money of any
stranger which is not of thy seed.
He He that is born in thine house and he
that is bought with thy money must needs
be circumcised and my covenant
>> listen. He said the stranger that's
bought with money. That money represent
the blood of Jesus
>> and born in my house must need be
circumcised. Those are two strong words.
Isn't that correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Sir,
>> mandatory.
>> Abraham Abraham ain't opening his mouth.
He listening, ain't it?
>> Yes.
>> Y
>> and my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant.
And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul shall be cut off
from his people. He hath broken my
covenant.
>> From a what? Just Israel and a stranger.
>> That applies to everybody. Got to be
>> everybody. He And if he is not
circumcised, he going he going to be
what?
cut off
>> shall be cut off from his people. He
have broken my covenant.
>> Can God lie?
>> No.
>> Impossible.
>> Okay. Cut off. That mean you going to
end up in the lake of fire. That was
that was
>> that was verse 14. You read to that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, let's go show you what's going to
happen when Jesus kingdom is back on
this earth.
Ezekiel 43 would tell you that Jesus was
on earth and he came by way of the east
gate. But we're going to start at
Ezekiel 44. We going to read one and two
and then we going to skip.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 44:es
1 and 2 say, "Then he brought me back
the way of the gate of the outward
sanctuary, which looked towards the
east, and it was shut. Then saith the
Lord unto me, "This gate shall be shut.
It shall not be open, and no man shall
enter in by it, because the Lord, the
God of Israel, has entered in by it.
Therefore, it shall be shut."
>> So that's that's that's in Jerusalem.
The Lord is back on earth.
>> He said, "I want you to keep this gate
shut because the God of Israel came
through this church. They said I don't
this gate I don't want no man coming to
it. That mean is on earth. Isn't that
correct?
>> That's right.
>> Gang is here.
>> Down and read verse four.
>> Then brought he me the way of the north
gate before the house. And I looked and
behold the glory of the Lord filled the
house of the Lord and I fell upon my
face.
Do not Jesus was in in in the temple
that going to be built by Zerubbabel and
his people. Now, let's see what else
happened. Skip down and skip down and
read verse six and seven. Pay attention
to what he's going to say now. Who is
the one that's called the stranger to
break his covenant? Six and seven. Go
ahead. and th and thou shalt say to the
rebellious, even to the house of Israel,
thus sayeth the Lord God, oh ye house of
Israel, let it suffice you of all your
abominations
and that ye have
he's talking to the Israel point blank,
no stranger, no other people, talking
strictly to the house of Israel. Let it
suffice you of all of your abomination.
Let's see what he talking about. Go
ahead.
>> And that ye have brought into my
sanctuary strangers, uncircumcised in
heart and uncircumcised in flesh to be
in my sanctuary.
>> That kills that so-called being
circumcised in the fle in the mind,
don't it?
>> Yes, it does.
>> The Lord covered both of them, didn't
it?
>> Yes, he did.
It's an abomination cuz you done brought
strangers into my sanctuary,
uncircumcised
in the heart or in the flesh. Go ahead.
To pollute it, even mine house when ye
offer my bread, the fat and the blood,
and they have broken my covenant because
of all your abominations.
>> Your abominations.
>> He's talking to Israel. The only
Israelites they see in the whole Bible
that said that the Gentiles which is a
stranger don't have to be circumcised
was when Paul and Peter then went when
Paul and Peter was arguing they went
along with Paul and it wasn't Paul
Israelite.
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> Wasn't the apostles Israelite?
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> So read it again. Who called the
stranger to break God's company?
>> In that ye have brought into my
sanctuary strangers, uncircumcised in
heart and uncircumcised in flesh to be
in my sanctuary to pollute it, even mine
house. When ye offered my when ye offer
my bread, the fat, and the blood, and
they have broken my covenant, because of
all your abominations.
So they broke the covenant of God to
strangers. That's why you got Gentiles
running around talking about you ain't
got to be circumcised.
Circumcision for the Jews. No, the
circum wasn't no Jew when when when God
gave his uh uh uh circumcision to
Abraham. Was there a Jew?
>> Nope.
>> No.
>> Was there Israelite?
>> Nope.
>> No.
>> So now what did the Lord say to the
stranger? Get down and read verse N.
Thus sayeth the Lord God, no stranger,
uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh, shall enter into
my sanctuary of any stranger that is
among the children of Israel.
That mean now you can't even enter into
the Lord's circum uh uh uh uh
into in the Lord's sanctuary because if
you ain't circumcised
he's saying stranger because that's who
he knew it was going to come up in and
somebody going to say that the stranger
don't have to be circumcised.
>> We got three more places I want to go
cuz I want I want to kill this dead in
the water cuz this keep coming up. Go to
Exodus the 12th chapter.
And we're going to look because that's
when the Lord instituted the Passover.
That's where he told him, "Get a lamb.
Put him up at the a lamb of the first
year without blemish and put him up on
the 10th day. And then I want you to uh
uh uh kill the lamb
on the 14th day of the month a and take
his blood and put it over dope post."
And he said, "When I'm cuz I'm going to
come through Egypt and I'm going to kill
the firstborn of everything man and
beast and when I see the blood." He
didn't say, "When I see Israel, he said
when I see the blood, I'mma pass over
them." So that's where the word Passover
come from. Cuz if you're under the
blood, the Lord will see the blood and
he won't so your see your sin. So he
going to pass over you.
But then there's an oddness to this
Passover that you have to observe. And
let's see what that ordinance is. Read
it. We're going to read 42 and 43 first.
Read it.
>> Okay. Exodus 12:42 and 43 says,
"It is a night to be much observed unto
the Lord for bringing them out from the
land of Egypt." Uhuh. Exodus 12.
>> Yes. Exodus 12.
42 and 43.
>> Exodus 12 verse 42 and 43 starts.
>> That's it, sir.
>> That's it. That's what you're looking
for, guest caller.
>> Uh I'm I'm looking
>> 43 says, "This is the ordinance of the
Passover."
>> That's 43. That's 43.
>> Okay. Well, 43 then. Okay.
And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the ordinance of the Passover,
there shall no stranger eat thereof."
>> Uhhuh.
>> But every man's servant that is bought
for money, when thou has circumcised
him, then shall he eat thereof.
So that mean you had to be circumcised
whether you Israel or a stranger to the
to eat of the Passover. Right.
>> Correct.
>> Yeah.
>> Now read from 48 and 49.
And when a stranger shall join with thee
and will keep the Passover to the Lord,
let all his males be circumcised,
and then let him come near and keep it.
And he shall be as one that is born in
the land. For no uncircumcised person
shall eat thereof.
One law shall be to him that is homeborn
and unto the stranger that sjjoth among
you.
>> So are the Gentiles strangers?
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> So that mean that whatever Israel had to
do, the Gentiles had to do, didn't it?
>> One law.
>> Yes, sir.
>> One law. So if you going to come and
partake of the Passover, you had to be
circumcised.
>> Yeah.
>> Every physical thing have a spiritual
meaning. Let's see what the who is the
real Passover. Go to first Corinthians
the 5th chapter and read verse 7.
>> 1 Corinthians 5 and 7 says, "Purge out
therefore the old leaven that ye may be
a new lump as ye are unleavened. For
even Christ, our Passover is sacrificed
for us.
>> So who is the Passover?
>> Jesus.
>> So now if he's the Passover and you had
to be circumcised uh uh to partake of
the Passover, can you partake of Jesus?
>> Nope. Nope.
>> No.
One more place and this the end of it.
Go to Galatians the 30th chapter and I
want you to read verse starting at verse
26- 29. Okay. Galatians 3 26-29
says, "For ye are all the children of
God by faith in Christ Jesus. For as
many of you as has been baptized into
Christ have put on Christ. There is
neither
>> listen. He said you the children of
Christ through Jesus." Ain't that
correct?
>> Correct.
>> As many
uh in Christ have put on Christ. So we
talking we got to go through Jesus cuz
he's the Passover.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> There is neither Jew nor Greek. There is
neither bond nor free. There is neither
male nor female. For ye are all one in
Christ Jesus.
And if ye be Christ, then are ye
Abraham's seed and hes according to the
promise.
Now,
what
did the Lord say to Abraham?
How many of his seed have to be
circumcised?
>> Oh,
>> so Paul.
>> So Paul took you right on back to the
beginning and that have not changed. No
man can change God's commandments.
And the circumcision was never about
Israel. That's why Paul uh uh uh
circumcised Timothy. It was it was about
the Gentile, the stranger. But then God
had already set that in order.
So if you're a stranger, a
non-Israelite,
then uh uh you
if you want to get into God's sanctuary
in his kingdom, you better get
circumcised. must needs.
>> And as far as uh you Israel, God was so
passionate about circumcision that he
started to kill Moses because he forgot
to circumcise his own son.
>> But his wife circumcised knife. So I'm
going say to you the person that
answered this question, no,
there ain't nothing that terminates the
circumcision. If you don't want to be
then believe God because he can't lie.
Cuz God said you going to be cut off
from among your people. I will be
looking upon you in the lake of fire.
That's all I got to say.
>> Hey, guess can we read that Luke 2 and
verse 21 and see what happened? The one
that gave Abraham that told Abraham that
he had to be circumcised.
This God here. Let's see what happened
to him in verse 21. And that one verse
Luke 2 and 21 what did it say brother?
>> And when 8 days were accomplished for
the circumcising of the child his name
was called Jesus which was named of the
angel before he was conceived in the
womb.
>> So
>> so goes the shepherd go all the sheep.
>> What you say brother?
>> So Jesus had to go there.
>> Yes he did.
Just like Jesus had to get baptized when
John the Baptist didn't want to do it.
He told himself it to be so that all
righteousness would be be fulfilled.
>> Yep.
Yep.
>> Yeah. Ain't no need of you getting
baptized cuz you can't get under the new
covenant because Jesus is the Passover.
That's all to it. That is it. Yep.
That's it. So circumcision is alive
today and tomorrow. And hey, please do
it if you are not. Okay, Sister Deborah,
we're gonna go with the time check.
>> Yes, the time is uh 8:56.
We are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, August the 20th, 2025.
Shanqua A Joby says in Romans 12 6-8
discussing the gifts God gives us while
Galatians 5 22 and 23 describes the
characteristics of the Holy Spirit.
How can one know if the Holy Spirit is
within them?
All right. When you got that word and
you're keeping them holy commandments,
hey, that's a great start. Let's go to
Romans 12 6 through8 and open it up to
the panel.
>> Romans 12 verse 6-8.
Romans 12:6-8 says, "Having then gifts
differing according to the grace that is
given to us, whether prophecy, let us
prophesy according to the portion of
faith." Or ministry, let us wait on our
ministering. Or he that teacheth on
teaching, or he that exhorteth, on
exhortation. He that giveth, let him do
it with slim simplicity. He that ruleth
with diligence. He that showeth mercy
with cheerfulness.
>> All right. Then it's talking about the
many gifts that the Lord is talking
about
>> and also a little fruits of the spirit
in there.
>> What was that other verse?
>> That's what that basically is. The the
fruits of the spirit. You shall know
them by their behavior.
>> And they not understanding.
>> All right. What's that?
>> And how do you know if you got the Holy
Ghost in you?
>> And keeping that word, them
commandments.
>> Keeping that word. Let's go look at
something real quick.
>> Let's go to St. John the 6th chapter.
>> 514 right quick.
Okay. St. John 6 verse 51-54 says, "I am
the living bread which came down from
heaven. If any man eat of this bread, he
shall live forever, and the bread that I
will give is my flesh, which I will give
for the life of the world." The Jews
therefore strove among themselves,
saying, "How can this man give us his
flesh to eat?" Then Jesus said unto
them, "Verily, verily, I say unto you,
except ye eat the flesh of the Son of
man and drink his blood, ye have no life
in you."
>> Go ahead.
>> Whosoever eateth my flesh and drinkkeeth
my blood hath eternal life, and I will
raise him up at the last day.
>> Now, you can't ask for more than eternal
life, right?
>> No. Skip now to verse
>> because they was having a problem with
eating his flesh. Verse 20 60 rather
verse 60 to read it.
>> Many therefore of his disciples when
they had heard this said this is an hard
saying who can hear it.
>> When Jesus knew
>> when Jesus knew in himself that his
disciples murmured at it, he said unto
them, "Doeth this offend you?"
>> Uh-huh. Skip down and read verse 63.
>> It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profiteth nothing. The words that
I speak unto you, they are spirit and
they are life.
>> Wait a minute. The words that I speak
unto you. So he not telling you to eat
his flesh.
>> Just like he wasn't telling Adam Eve to
eat some apple. He's saying eat my word.
It is spirit and that is life.
>> Get down now to verse 66. and uh uh and
read to uh uh uh
>> 68.
>> Okay. Verse 66 says, "From that time
many of his disciples went back and
walked no more with him. Then said Jesus
unto the twel, will ye also go away?"
Then Simon Peter answered answered him,
"Lord, to whom shall we go? Thou has the
words of eternal life."
Now, so it's the words is the So when
you are full of the word of God, you are
full of the Holy Ghost or the Holy
Spirit and the fruits of the spirit is
your behavior. You won't steal. You
won't kill. You won't commit adultery.
You won't lie on your neighbor. You
won't fornicate.
>> You won't pollute the day. That is the
fruits of it. Your behavior. That's all
I got to say.
>> All right. and brother James, let's go
to that last place they ask about that
Galatians 5 and let's read about some of
these fruits of the spirit. Okay.
>> So read that 22 23 and then 25.
>> Okay. Galatians uh five. You said five,
correct?
>> Yes. 22 23.
>> Okay.
>> And 25.
>> But the fruit of the spirit is love. is
love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance. Against such there is no
law.
>> If we live in the spirit, let us also
walk in the spirit.
>> Yeah. So it's the word of God that
teaches us that we have to put on these
fruits of the spirit of love, joy,
peace, longsuffering, gentle gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness, temperance,
which is self-control. All these things
are good for your edification and for
your walk with Christ. And hey, and if
we're going to live in the spirit, let
us also walk. So don't only talk it,
walk it as well. Anybody else? supposed
to tell you that love is the fulfillment
of the law.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yep. For God is love.
>> That's it.
>> Yes. All right, Sister Deborah. Time
check.
>> Yes. The time is 9:02.
>> We have ran out of time. We want to
thank everybody from all around the
world who tuned in with us this evening
and sent in those questions. We had joy
in taking part in helping to shed some
light. So we say if you submitted a
question, we never have a chance to get
to it. Please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah, take it, put it in rotation.
And so we say that until we all come
together again, please be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as brother
James closes us out. Our Father, which
art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread, and forgive us our debts,
as we forgive our debtors, and lead us
not into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. in Jesus
name we pray. Amen.